Um, I'll start you off with just what
was it that attracted you to the
opportunity here?
Yeah, I mean there was a lot. I was I
was really excited about Kellen being,
you know, obviously played the position
and uh
uh him and I have known each other for a
little bit and I was excited to
explore that relationship and
um just love what he's doing with the
organization and
uh
yeah, I mean I mean that was a big part
of it for me.
I know you mentioned him playing the
position, but you know, like you've you
were with the you were with Sean Payton,
with Mike McDaniel, now you're with
Kellen Moore. Like is there anything
about his offense maybe that stands out
to you as well and his approach to the
play calling spot?
Yeah, I think it would be a good fit for
what I feel like uh I'm good at. Um I
feel like he does a good job in in the
quarterback room of just um allowing the
guys to be their best selves and uh and
play the position well. So, I'm excited
about that and um
you know, I think he's done a good job
developing the guys that are there right
now.
Zack, 33 starts. How much does that help
you in your experience as you join the
Saints now?
Yeah, I think a lot. I mean I I I feel
like I've learned a lot of the last 5
years and uh
hopefully I can use that going in and
just be able to pick up the offense
quickly and um
and have a good idea that I've I've run
most of these things before and and at
some point in the past and
maybe they're a little different, but
just helps me adjust a little bit
quicker and then obviously the game
experience helps for sure.
Yeah.
How would you characterize those those 5
years? You know, difficult, you know,
rocky, how would you characterize them?
Yeah, I mean crazy, a lot of learning.
Um I'm extremely grateful for just the
opportunity to be in the NFL and how
hard that is every single day and uh
um met a lot of good people and good
friends along the way and uh hopefully I
can just con- continue to keep learning
and getting better.
Zack, what do you see your role here as?
Just how you coming into this?
Yeah, I mean I'm going in just trying to
compete. Whatever that means, uh you
know, I can't control
where I sit or or what's going on from
the the quarterback position or
anything. So, for me it's just, you
know, being a good teammate, get to know
the guys, do everything I can to learn
and study and uh
do the best I can and if I get an
opportunity to play at any point,
whether that's preseason or season or
you know, practice, it doesn't matter.
You know, just go out there and do my
best and just try and help the team.
Zack, how have you sort of evolved your
mindset and approach
uh in the last few years trying to
decide what's most important to you now
now that it's been sort of backup roles
like who you're working with, how much
playing time you get, how much chance
you get to start, how much you can
develop. Like what are your priorities
and how did that sort of affect why you
like the Saints?
Yeah, priority for me is getting into an
offense with
that that I feel like fits me
um
and I felt like, you know, with Kellen
and our our offensive coordinator and QB
coach as well that I feel like it's a
good fit there and um somebody that
knows how to develop the position the
right way and handle it the right way
and uh
I like what we do protection wise and uh
scheme wise. So, um you know, that
stuff's important and then, you know,
the rest of it if I just go out there
and I I do my best and I feel like
things will work out.
What are maybe some of the the parts of
your game that you feel best fit what uh
you know, the offense here does?
Yeah, just a lot of the rhythm and
timing, the footwork stuff. Uh their
ability to play fast and with high
tempo, get out of the pocket,
quarterbacks that are mobile.
Uh
just uh you know, as I get into more of
the schematics of it and and learning
the offense, I feel like it's uh it's
similar to like what I was doing in
Denver uh with coach Payton as well and
uh what you kind of see from the Rams
and Matthew Stafford as well. Uh a
little bit of gunslinger and the ability
to just play ball. So, I'm excited about
that.
Zack, how much was of a sales job was it
to you or how much was it you
identifying New Orleans saying this is
where I want to go?
Yeah, there were some other teams I was
looking at and um
you know, I know New Orleans is in a
little bit of like a rebuild as well and
you know, that can be a plus or minus,
however you look at it, but uh I felt
like for me I just picked based off of
priorities like finding somebody that
had played the position like I said, an
offense that I felt comfortable with
that I could go in and play well, uh a
great fan base, great culture, a great
place to live, uh
so, you know, that stuff was maybe more
important to me than than some of the
other things you look at in the process
of free agency.
Hey,
kind of piggybacking off of that a
little bit. You've mentioned development
a couple times and you said that you you
saw some good development out of the
quarterbacks here under Kellen. Like was
that important to you as well just
finding a place where you could kind of
grow as a player?
Yeah, no doubt. Just continue to learn
the game and um you know, from from
three individuals on the offensive side
for me at least that uh you know, know
it really well especially from a
quarterback standpoint and can help me
just just be my best best self and that
was kind of part of the thought process
is like where can I go that's going to
help me be the best player I can be.
Do you know Tyler at all?
Uh I think funny enough we were actually
in the same Elite 11 class in high
school. He probably doesn't remember me
even being there, but uh he was the five
star, you know, all the offers from
everybody. And I you know, I was just
like a a three star quarterback with
just a few Mountain West offers and
couple Pac-12 offers back then and uh
yeah, and then we both went our separate
ways and I don't think we've ever talked
in person or or really met up much, but
I've always been kind of able to follow
his career from afar a little bit and uh
you know, he had a good year. I was
excited for him and we've we've texted a
little bit since I've uh you know,
committed to go to to the Saints and um
>> [clears throat]
>> yeah, we're excited to see where that
relationship goes. It's crazy how the
league works out that way, right? Like
he he transfers, he gets an opportunity
somewhere else and he does really well
and I go to BYU and and play early and
and don't have a very long career there
and get to go to league quick. So, it's
crazy how it works. I'm going into year
six, he's going into year two and we're
the same age. It's pretty crazy.
Do you see is there something in the
last few years when you kind of were in
more of a backup role like helping the
starter? Like do you enjoy that? Is that
um like is that an aspect of football
you enjoy and what what what what's kind
of your take on that?
Yeah, I don't know if I would look at it
from like a helping the starter
standpoint like like like I'm a a coach,
but for I think the just the room, just
having a good relationship between me,
Tyler, Spence and like the ability to
just like all of us bouncing ideas off
of each other, learning from each other
in practice, watching film together,
kind of just talking about what we see,
I think is the benefit. You know, it's
it's a little different than my role
um you know, with with some guys like
like Aaron Rodgers for example that like
kind of took on like a like a coach in
the room for example. Like I don't I
don't put myself as like a hey, I'm
going to like sit here and uh you know,
run run the meeting rooms or anything
like that, but I do think
uh us bouncing ideas is always a good
thing.
How important was Aaron to your career
and what did what you kind of learn from
him?
Yeah, well obviously our time together
was pretty short. We just got, you know,
the OTAs and uh training camp, but I
enjoyed our time together in the offense
we played in and
and the footwork and um
you know, some of the things we did uh I
thought was really cool for me to learn
and to see after my first 2 years, which
was uh very different. So, I enjoyed
that and then obviously once he'd gotten
hurt, uh you know, I didn't I didn't get
I didn't get to see him much. He was
doing rehab at I think in California.
So,
uh didn't see him for the entire year
and then obviously the next year I
wasn't there. So, um I enjoyed our our
time together and feel like I learned a
lot about football while he was there.
Does the Does the fact that you, Tyler,
Spencer, I mean you guys you as you
observed are all, you know, right around
the same age. What kind of impact does
that have
um in that room and especially on what
you were just talking about with you
guys being comfortable bouncing ideas
off of each other, things like that?
Yeah, I think it's fun. I mean we're all
still pretty young and competitive and
just want to be our best uh the best
players that we can all be and and help
the team win. And so, I think it'll be
uh
you know, really good to just have that
in the room.
Just wanted to follow up on something
you said earlier. Did Did you know
Kellen before this at all? Like had you
known him over the years or is there any
picture
>> talked a little bit in the past. He was
he was close with uh
John Beck and the 3DQB guys that I had
trained with as well and
um I'd always followed his career. I was
actually committed to Boise State uh
coming out of high school for about 8
months. So, you know, a lot of that ties
well and how I had followed his career
and then um you know, we had just said
what's up back and forth there much, not
not a ton to it and then um you know,
obviously it's always cool to see former
quarterbacks getting the coaching and
have as much uh success as he's had
early on.
Zack, there's there's been so many
stories in recent years of of of highly
drafted quarterbacks kind of making the
most of their second chances, whether
it's Sam Darnold or Baker Mayfield or
Malik Willis now. Like have you Have you
talked to anyone who's gone through that
process or have you just watched
and learned from from how they've gone
about their process to kind of map out,
you know, a a best plan for you and and
knowing that that it could still be a,
you know, just a later than better late
than never situation?
Yeah, it's always tough, right? I
haven't really talked to any of those
guys about it, but you know, watching
them from afar it's been cool to see the
success they've had and just being able
to stay
humble, working hard and and
you know, just taking every opportunity
they can and that's really what it is
for me. Like wherever I end up, whatever
reps I get, you know, I can't control a
lot of the things that come with it at
this point, so it doesn't matter. Like I
need to go out there and just
enjoy playing the game, put my best on
tape, and and just let the rest kind of
take care of itself. And if that
opportunity ever comes, um you know,
being ready for it, but I don't I
wouldn't say it's something I
necessarily like,
you know, try and have an entire like
road map planned out for it. It's just
you know what? Just taking advantage of
every opportunity I have right now, not
worrying about what the future holds,
and
uh just being grateful for every second
I have in the league.
In what way are you a better quarterback
than ever before now after what you've
been able to work on the last few years?
Yeah, I think the mindset
you know, the mindset obviously just
with the whole New York thing and just
how the league has gone for me. You
know, it's been tough, but I feel like
it all happened for a reason. I was able
to learn a lot and
um a lot of things about my game, the
way I approach the game, the
um maybe a lot of the thoughts I had
about the game, and
at the end of the day it's all a good
thing, so
uh I feel like that's something that's
beneficial for me going forward.
What did you kind of learn throughout
that process just in terms of managing
expectations? I mean, Taylor right now
is the guy that's got a lot of
expectation around him, you know, coming
off of that rookie year. And so just
curious about your kind of vantage point
on, you know, that skill set as a
quarterback in managing the expectations
that are external to what it is that
you're trying to achieve.
Yeah, it's tough. I mean, a lot of that
stuff you can't control and and it feels
like uh
it's heavy. Like the weight of it all
can be heavy. Um especially when I was
in that New York media market as well
and um
I felt like
you know, if it was me now, I probably
would have approached it a little bit
different and just understanding like
it's a game at the end of the day. I'm
going to go out there and put my put my
best on on the field and be able to live
with the results and and not feel like I
have to be the one that does it all and
not feel like uh
you know, if if I'm not, you know, the
one that flips the entire organization
around that, you know, it was all just a
failure or whatever. You know, I feel
like just going in there and just
simplifying your mindset and being like
I'm going to continue on getting better
and focus on one thing one day at a time
and the rest will be taken care of
itself.
Was the non-Saints black and gold hat a
conscientious choice or pure
coincidence? And if it was a
conscientious choice, how long did it
take you to find that one?
Yeah, someone sent me this in the mail a
few weeks ago, so I guess it was a sign,
right?
>> [laughter]
[snorts]